{"tossups": [{"question": "This man needed Archibald Roane to cast the tiebreaking vote to defeat John Sevier for commander of the Tennessee militia. A Scottish merchant and a marine who served under Edward Nicolls were the subject of a trial overseen by this man. This man defeated the forces of Menawa at a decisive defeat for the Red Stick Confederacy. That battle paved the way for this man\u2019s capture of Pensacola. For ten points, name this American general in the War of 1812 and future U.S. president.", "answer": "Andrew<em><b> Jackson</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "These institutions were the object of efforts to preserve traditional mores through the Falloux Laws which extended the Guizot Laws. Leo Collard reversed many reforms made to private institutions of this type by Pierre Hamel\u2019s Christian Social Party. Belgium underwent two political \u201cwars\u201d named after these institutions. These institutions were secularized through laicite by Jules Ferry in a series of 1880s laws. For ten points, name these institutions from which Catholic curricula were phased out.", "answer": "<em><b> School</b></em>s (accept Catholic<em><b> school</b></em>s)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In this area, Roland Burris cited pollution concerns when he sued a gun club founded by men like Oscar Mayer and Philip Wrigley. During a 1968 trial, Abbie Hoffman claimed that it would have been better if protests had been allowed in this area ten miles away from a Democratic Nominating Convention. Found in its city\u2019s North Side along Lake Michigan, for ten points, name this largest public park in Chicago, named for a president buried some 200 miles to its southwest.", "answer": "<em><b> Lincoln</b></em> Park", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man appointed William Mann to head a division named for the inclusion of members from many states. This creator of the Rainbow Division spoke of the \u201cfulfillment... of [his] boyish hopes and dreams\u201din a speech describing a group of people who \u201cjust fade away.\u201d This man gave the \u201cOld Soldiers Never Die\u201d speech 19 years after he defeated the Bonus Army. Relieved by Truman during the Korean War, this is, for ten points, what five-star general who led the Allied war effort in the Pacific?", "answer": "Douglas<em><b> MacArthur</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "After this company was accused of violating the Sherman Act in 1969, it spent 13 years locked in the longest antitrust suit in history. A future CEO of this company claimed \u201cwe get paid for working with our heads,\u201d inspiring this company\u2019s motto \u201cTHINK.\u201d This company\u2019s largest research facility is named for its first CEO Thomas Watson, who also names this company\u2019s A.I. system that was victorious on Jeopardy! For ten points, name this technology company nicknamed \u201cBig Blue.\u201d", "answer": "<em><b> IBM</b></em> (accept<em><b> International Business Machines</b></em> Corporation) Page 1", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "An attempted assassination of this man while at 56 Hope Road is explored in A Brief History of Seven Killings by Marlon James. This musician joined People\u2019s National Party leader Michael Manley and Manley\u2019s political rival Edward Seaga at a 1978 Peace Concert. As a symbol of black resistance, this singer wrote a song about Black U.S. cavalry regiments titled \u201cBuffalo Soldier.\u201d Bunny Wailer and Peter Tosh were bandmates of, for ten points, what Reggae artist of \u201cOne Love\u201d?", "answer": "Bob<em><b> Marley</b></em>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "A black woman gave this man a bouquet of flowers which he accepted while speaking at the Independent Order of Pole-Bearers Association. This man\u2019s most decisive victory came against Samuel Sturgis at the Battle of Brice\u2019s Crossroads. Lionel Booth\u2019s interracial forces were massacred by this man at Fort Pillow. An organization founded by this man in Pulaski, Tennessee in 1868 named him Grand Wizard. For ten points, name this Confederate Civil War general who founded the Ku Klux Klan.", "answer": "Nathan Bedford<em><b> Forrest</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A Fluxus artist from this country prompted audience members to cut away her clothing with scissors in Cut Piece. Many Infinity Rooms have been made by a polka dot-loving artist from this country. Annie Leibovitz photographed a performance artist from this country naked next to her husband hours before his assassination in 1980. For ten points, name this home country of Yayoi Kusama and the wife of John Lennon, Yoko Ono.", "answer": "<em><b> Japan</b></em>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This king married a woman who had earlier been married to a knight named John Grey of Groby, who died at the Second Battle of St. Albans. Two of this man\u2019s sons died mysterious deaths during the reign of his brother and became known as the Princes in the Tower. This husband of Elizabeth of Woodville defeated Henry VI at the Battle of Tewkesbury, bringing an end to the House of Lancaster. For ten points, name this king of the House of York, the elder brother of Richard III.", "answer": "<em><b> Edward IV</b></em> Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A speech in which this ruler exclaimed, \u201cGentlemen, let us have no dreams!\u201d sparked the January Uprising in Poland. On the day of his death, this monarch signed the Loris-Melikov Constitution, though his reactionary successor had it repealed. This monarch created local government councils known as zemstvos in his 1861 Emancipation Reform. For ten points, name this Russian Tsar who freed the serfs but was assassinated by the revolutionary group People\u2019s Will.", "answer": "<em><b> Alexander II</b></em> (accept<em><b> Alexander the Liberator</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "That region is now a modern nation.", "answer": "<em><b> Finland</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Argentine anarchist Severino Di Giovanni attempted to assassinate this man by blowing up his train. This man was put in charge of relief efforts following the Great Mississippi Flood. This man created\u201cmeatless Monday\u201d and \u201cwheatless Wednesdays\u201d while head of the US Food Administration during World War One. This man won election to his highest office by promising a \u201cchicken in every pot and a car in every garage\u201d in a race against Al Smith. For ten points, name this president during the Great Depression.", "answer": "Herbert Clark<em><b> Hoover</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In 2006, this leader claimed that anyone supporting Aleksandr Milinkievich would face having their necks wrung \u201cas one might a duck.\u201d This man won a 1994 election over his country\u2019s incumbent prime minister Vyacheslav Kebich. Hugo Chavez once called this man\u2019s country \u201ca model social state.\u201d This man once replied that it was \u201cbetter to be a dictator\u201d than to be gay when a German foreign minister referred to him as \u201cEurope\u2019s last dictator.\u201d For ten points, name this longtime president of Belarus.", "answer": "Alexander<em><b> Lukashenko</b></em>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man wrote that \u201c[Bush] was rarely the voice of realism on the Iraq war\u201d in his book The War Within. A 2003 leak supposedly made this man the first reporter to know that Valerie Plame worked for the CIA. FBI Associate Director Mark Felt was revealed to be the source reporting to this man under the alias \u201cDeep Throat.\u201d This man began reporting for the Washington Post in 1971 where he met Carl Bernstein. For ten points, name this man whose work led to Richard Nixon\u2019s resignation.", "answer": "Bob<em><b> Woodward</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "For his gallantry during this operation, David Lord received a Victoria Cross after being shot down on a resupply mission. Stanislaw Sosabowski commanded Polish troops during this operation, where the XXX [thirty] Corps\u2019s failure to relieve a force in time led to a disastrous battle at Arnhem. During this operation, the First Allied Airborne Army intended to capture bridges to open a British ground assault. For ten points, named this Allied invasion in the Netherlands that failed to secure passage over the Rhine.", "answer": "Operation<em><b> Market Garden</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Taxi driver Homer Nida was killed in this city by Roy Belton, who was later lynched. A riot in this city began after Dick Rowland was accused of assaulting elevator operator Sarah Page. A 2001 state commission\u2019s study of that riot concluded that this city conspired with the white mob. During that riot in this city, the neighborhood of Greenwood, deemed \u201cBlack Wall Street,\u201d was firebombed. For ten points, name this city, the site of a 1921 race riot in Oklahoma.", "answer": "<em><b> Tulsa</b></em>, Oklahoma", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After viewing the damage caused at Pearl Harbor, this man claimed \u201cthe Japanese language will be spoken only in hell.\u201d The phrase \u201cHit hard, hit fast, hit often\u201d was a popular U.S. (+) Navy slogan that originated with this man. A message sent to this man that popularized the phrase \u201cthe world wonders\u201d was sent after he fell for a trap set by the Northern Force that led this man to move Task Force 34 out of position. That message was sent by (*)</b> Chester Nimitz to this man during the Battle of Leyte Gulf. For ten points, name this U.S. Navy admiral during the Second World War, nicknamed \u201cBull.\u201d", "answer": "William \u201cBull\u201d<em><b> Halsey</b></em> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man signed the Treaty of Durham after defeating a Scottish rebellion by David I at the Battle of the Standard. This man was captured by Robert of Gloucester at the Battle of Lincoln shortly after he had crossed the English Channel to take the throne after learning of William (+) Adelin\u2019s death in the White Ship Disaster. In exchange for peace, this ruler signed the Treaty of Winchester to allow (*)</b> Henry II, the son of his rival, to succeed him. For ten points, name this English king who fought with empress Matilda in the Anarchy, the only British ruler between the houses of Anjou and Normandy.", "answer": "<em><b> Stephen</b></em> of Blois", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>William R. Cooper argued that this god was the primary inspiration for Jesus Christ. The Younger version of this god was depicted sucking his finger while the Elder version\u2019s eyes were the sun and the moon. According to (+) Macrobius\u2019s Chronicon and the works of Epiphanius of Salamis, this god was worshiped during winter solstice festivals. A conflict with Egypt\u2019s southern neighbors may have influenced this god\u2019s conflict with his uncle (*) </b>Set, who had ripped this god\u2019s father apart to usurp the throne. For ten points, name this falcon headed god of the sky, the son of Isis and Osiris.", "answer": "<em><b> Horus</b></em> (accept<em><b> Her</b></em>, accept<em><b> Heru</b></em>, accept<em><b> Hor</b></em>, accept<em><b> Har</b></em>)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "<b>The first British minister in this country was John Wilton who was deployed following the creation of the Trucial States. This country was shelled by the British East India Company in retaliation for piracy in 1821. This country\u2019s Bani Khalid tribes were conquered by a coalition of the Emirate of Diriyah, (+) Oman, and the Ottoman Empire in the late 1700s. This country has been ruled by the House of Thani since 1868. In 2010, this country was chosen to be the first Arab country to host the (*)</b> FIFA World Cup in 2022. For ten points, name this peninsular country where the state-owned Al Jazeera Media Network was founded.", "answer": "State of<em><b> Qatar</b></em> Page 9", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The instigator of this event suggested it was justified by a false flag attack on a radio station in Silesia, the Gleiwitz incident. This event was codenamed Operation White and featured ineffective cavalry charges on horseback against (+) panzers. This event was decided in its early days by the \u201cBattle of the Border\u201d and culminated with the Battle of Kock. The Katyn Forest massacre was perpetrated shortly after this event concluded. (*) </b>Germany and the Soviet Union split up the spoils of, for ten points, what aggressive action on September 1, 1939 that began World War Two?", "answer": "<em><b> Invasion</b></em> of<em><b> Poland</b></em> (accept<em><b> September Campaign</b></em>, 1939<em><b> Defensive War</b></em>, or<em><b> Poland </b><b>Campaign</b></em>, accept other answers that indicate<em><b> Poland</b></em> being attacked by Germany)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A document drafted in this city called for a bicameral parliament divided into a House of States and a House of Commons. The May Uprisings arose as a campaign to recognize a document that had been drafted in this city\u2019s (+) St. Paul\u2019s Church in the wake of the March Revolution. Jury trials for criminals and a constitutional monarchy led by Frederick William IV were among the provisions of that document created by this city\u2019s (*)</b> namesake 1848 parliament that was the first freely elected parliament in Germany. For ten points, name this city located on the River Main [MINE]", "answer": "<em><b> Frankfurt</b></em> am Main, Germany", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>The protagonist of this work is buried at Fort Adams after dying on board the USS Levant, aboard which he created a painting showing a bald eagle that has lightning \u201cblazing from its beak.\u201d The protagonist of this work is thought to have been inspired by the Ohio Democrat (+) Clement Vallandigham, and the work itself was written to bolster Union support in the North. In this work, an accomplice of Aaron Burr named (*)</b> Philip Nolan is exiled to prevent him hearing about developments in the United States after 1807. For ten points, name this Edward Everett Hale short story about a figure banished from his homeland.", "answer": "\u201cThe<em><b> Man Without a Country</b></em>\u201d Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One commander at this battle decided against continuing a march along the Shunpike Road despite the fact that it would have caught the Confederates in the rear. Daniel Ruggles told his men to (+) \u201cget every gun you can find\u201d during one standoff in this battle. The author of Ben-Hur, Lew Wallace, was injured while commanding a division along the (*)</b> \u201cHornet\u2019s Nest\u201d at this battle which was alternatively named the Battle of Pittsburg Landing. For ten points, name this 1862 Civil War battle, a victory for the Ulysses S. Grant-led Army of the Tennessee.", "answer": "Battle of<em><b> Shiloh</b></em> (accept Battle of<em><b> Pittsburg Landing</b></em> before it is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}